<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal on Kandelvijaya</title>
    <link>http://kandelvijaya.com/tags/terminal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terminal on Kandelvijaya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Vijaya P. Kandelvijaya</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 17:16:52 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kandelvijaya.com/tags/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GTX March: Basic tips</title>
      <link>http://kandelvijaya.com/gtxmonthly/gtxTips_mar2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 17:16:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kandelvijaya.com/gtxmonthly/gtxTips_mar2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;git&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last few months, I spent my off work time migrating one of the old app to self hosted
Parse Server. Although, writing about Parse Server on dedicated Linux machine is out of scope for
this post, I got few useful points regarding the use of terminal and git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets say you have a website. You want to use &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;. When you &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;, it should
deploy your site automatically. Plus, your teammate should also be able to push and pull.
Lets do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-creating-a-bare-repo&#34;&gt;1. Creating a bare repo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bare repo is used for sharing code. Typically shared for collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bare repos have &lt;code&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt;(&lt;em&gt;for most case&lt;/em&gt;) extension on their path. For more detail
    read this blog post. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saintsjd.com/2011/01/what-is-a-bare-git-repository/&#34;&gt;Difference between bare and normal git repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a bare repo for a existing repository (which is usually the case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone --bare ~/my-website ~/my-website.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;my-website should be a normal git repository.&lt;/em&gt;
Creating a bare repo is easy too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone --bare init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read Terminal Section for; how to push the bare repo to server.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-git-hooks&#34;&gt;2. Git hooks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooks are like callbacks. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s a programming view. Anyways, hooks let you run script after some event occurs on git. The event could be push, commit, merge, pull or etc. Here, we will focus on &lt;code&gt;post-receive&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now say you moved the bare repo to the server machine, and want to configure git to
deploy the site when someone pushes to this repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd &amp;lt;yourpath&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;yourbarerepo.git&amp;gt;/hooks/
$ touch post-receive  // (1)
$ nano post-receive   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(1)&lt;/em&gt;:: &lt;em&gt;Hooks are just shell script with special filename.&lt;/em&gt;
Now we will clone the repo to a public website serving directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash

GIT_REPO=$HOME/&amp;lt;yourbarerepo.git&amp;gt;
WORKING_DIRECTORY=$HOME/WWW/&amp;lt;yourwebsitePublicDir&amp;gt;/

set -e

rm -rf $WORKING_DIRECTORY       # remove old files

git clone $GIT_REPO $WORKING_DIRECTORY  #clone new content

trap - EXIT
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, make the hook script executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ chmod +x post-receive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats the basics of automatic deployment. For more info please refer to:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-deploy-a-hugo-site-to-production-with-git-hooks-on-ubuntu-14-04&#34;&gt;This fantastic in depth deployment guide from DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;terminal&#34;&gt;Terminal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-background-job-yes-job&#34;&gt;1. Background job, yes job.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you ever want to run a script repeatedly 1 am in the morning OR every time there is a new content for the app to consume OR database backup, periodic emailing, OR what have you. Enter cron job. Dont get afraid. There&amp;rsquo;s just 1 line. Thats it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ crontab -e
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then edit the file. Lines starting with &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;, as you guessed, are comments.
At the end of the file, I could do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1 1 * * * ~/jobs/backupMongoDb.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save and exit. Every &lt;em&gt;1(first) minute of every 1(hour) of every * (day) , of every * (week) of every year&lt;/em&gt;
 run the script &lt;code&gt;~/jobs/backupMongoDb.sh&lt;/code&gt;. Simple and neat right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for the script part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh

BACKINGDIR=$HOME/backup/
DESTNAME=&amp;lt;yourappname&amp;gt;+`date +&amp;quot;%m-%d-%y&amp;quot;`

cd $BACKINGDIR
mongodump --db &amp;lt;yourdbname&amp;gt; -o $DESTNAME
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last command &lt;code&gt;mongodump&lt;/code&gt; is the one that will dump the database. Finally, make this
file executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ chmod +x ~/jobs/backupMongoDb.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could extend this script to remove the older directories in order to save space, zip the dumped database. This is left for your research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-zipping-and-scp-ping&#34;&gt;2. Zipping and Scp(ping)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets get back to where we created bare cloned repo. Now we need to transfer that to server.
We want to do it via the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ scp -r &amp;lt;yourBareRepo.git&amp;gt; &amp;lt;yourname&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;ServerIP-or-domain&amp;gt;:~/website/&amp;lt;yourBareRepo.git&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCP, stands for secure copy. For this step, you need to have local machine&amp;rsquo;s SSH Keys added to
the server beforehand. Transferring a file opens a network connection. Transferring 1000 files might need tons of connection to be opened and closed. This adds latency wherby 20 MB directory that contains 10000 files could take 10 minutes. Lets speed the transfer by transferring 1 file. 1 zipped file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ tar -czf bareRepo.zip &amp;lt;yourBareRepo.git&amp;gt;

$ scp bareRepo.zip &amp;lt;yourname&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;ServerIP-or-domain&amp;gt;:~/website/bareRepo.zip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have left for you to extract the zipped folder in the server. HINT: &lt;code&gt;$ man tar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on the local machine set the remote to be this bare repo on the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git remote add origin &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;SERVER_IP_ADDRESS&amp;gt;:website/bareRepo.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;xcode&#34;&gt;Xcode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-regexp-find-and-replace&#34;&gt;1. Regexp find and replace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, while at work in Zalando SE, I was refactoring Flexible Layout Kit. Every Element is represented by a &lt;strong&gt;ElementController&lt;/strong&gt; which has &lt;code&gt;var model: &amp;lt;Some&amp;gt;Element?&lt;/code&gt; by conforming to a protocol.
We have 25 element controller. During the refactor, lets suppose, I want to make all, &lt;code&gt;var model: &amp;lt;Some&amp;gt;Element?&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;var model: &amp;lt;Some&amp;gt;Element&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many manual ways. Xcode isn&amp;rsquo;t powerful like AndroidStudio when it comes to refactoring. The way to do it quickly is to regex find replace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kandelvijaya.com/img/GTXMarch-Xcode-FindReplace.png&#34; alt=&#34;Regexp find replace&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(.*)&lt;/strong&gt; is a capture group. It can be used later by referring it via &lt;strong&gt;$1&lt;/strong&gt; which is what we did in the replace section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-lldb-po-broken-fix&#34;&gt;2. LLDB &amp;lsquo;po&amp;rsquo; broken fix&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Swift came out, LLDB gets broken for various reason. It complains a lot. I cant debug effectively without &lt;code&gt;po&lt;/code&gt;. This is how I have been fixing this AST issue with LLDB. This is not the silver bullet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Clean the project. Restart Xcode. Try lldb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(IF above doesn&amp;rsquo;t work) Go to the derived data. Remove everything. Maybe &lt;code&gt;$rm -rf&lt;/code&gt; at that folder. Restart Xcode. Try lldb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(If above doesn&amp;rsquo;t work) Change the derived data directory. &lt;img src=&#34;http://kandelvijaya.com/img/GTX-March-xcodeLLDB.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Changeing Derived Data directory easy way&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks for reading until this point. Comments, suggestions and edits are appreciated. Cheers!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTX Nov: Bisecting, Emacs and killing line. </title>
      <link>http://kandelvijaya.com/gtxmonthly/gtxTips_nov2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 14:28:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kandelvijaya.com/gtxmonthly/gtxTips_nov2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this months GTX. How are you? Its cold here in Berlin. Lets get to this months
GTX(Git, Terminal, XCode) tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;git&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-finding-which-commit-broke-the-project-first&#34;&gt;1. Finding which commit broke the project first&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git-bisect&lt;/code&gt; is the command you are looking for if you happen to search for a commit in the
past week which silently broke the project and the CI is failing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to this command while at work from my colleague, @ramy_kfoury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git bisect start
$ git bisect bad                 # Current version is bad
$ git bisect good v2.6.13-rc2    # v2.6.13-rc2 is known to be good
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then git will stop at the middle commit. It uses binary search to narrow down possibilities. Then
you can test that commit. Testing can be running unit tests at that point, or a set of scripts or
manually validating the functionality. Depending on if the error is present or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git bisect good               # bad if the commit has problem
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we will be left with 1 commit, which is the one that introduced some faults. For more
in-depth usage please &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/docs/git-bisect&#34;&gt;read this brief reference guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-github-style-diff-on-terminal&#34;&gt;2. GitHub style diff on terminal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to see beautiful and clean diff on terminal? We&amp;rsquo;ve got one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diff_So_Fancy&lt;/strong&gt; is a plugin that does exactly like GitHub UI diff. To install,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ brew install diff-so-fancy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to use when required:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$git diff --color | diff-so-fancy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good part, to make it default, which i recommend, issue this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$git config --global core.pager &amp;quot;diff-so-fancy | less --tabs=4 -RFX&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more customization, take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/so-fancy/diff-so-fancy&#34;&gt;diff_so_fancy GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If for some reason, you prefer side-by-side diff, then there are 2 projects that are worth looking:
1. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ymattw/cdiff&#34;&gt;cdiff&lt;/a&gt;
2. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeffkaufman/icdiff&#34;&gt;icdiff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally haven&amp;rsquo;t used &lt;code&gt;icdiff&lt;/code&gt; and have limited exposure to &lt;code&gt;cdiff&lt;/code&gt;. I will continue with this topic
for the next month. Until then have fun bisecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;terminal&#34;&gt;Terminal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-emacs-editor-of-lifetime-for-some&#34;&gt;1. Emacs: Editor of lifetime (for some)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emacs was started 25 years ago but still remains both the source of inspiration to other
text editors and a powerful extensible text editor. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind to call it more than
a text editor to a mini operating system. You can browse web, create web browser and reply
email. There&amp;rsquo;s more. This is how Emacs differs from Vi/Vim. Its great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always like to do as much possible without losing context. Terminal is a most for me as
I learned and used Git to manage my projects. I don&amp;rsquo;t use GUI. So I must use terminal every
couple of minutes. I wanted terminal to do more. I wanted to use the text editor inside the
terminal. I wanted my text editor to be able to quickly edit commit message, Swift source
files and write my notes. I will probably go into the details of why I love text based note
taking and journal in some future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay lets get Emacs. You can see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ brew update
$ brew install emacs --with-cocoa
$ brew linkapps emacs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then should be able to run &lt;code&gt;emacs&lt;/code&gt; by issuing &lt;code&gt;$ emacs -nw&lt;/code&gt; in the terminal. If not, chances are
you have a conflicting system &lt;code&gt;emacs&lt;/code&gt;. On OSX/ mac OS emacs is installed by default. If your
installation doesn&amp;rsquo;t work then you can hop on this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wikemacs.org/wiki/Installing_Emacs_on_OS_X&#34;&gt;website guide&lt;/a&gt;
for troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the GUI Emacs then just issue &lt;code&gt;$emacs&lt;/code&gt;, the GUI is fairly simple but 2 superior things
to terminal mode is that the Fonts/Themes have broader color and size options. Second, you can use
the mouse. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that&amp;rsquo;s actually a + point or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot however go into the details of setting up Emacs in one post or in tips. I would nonetheless
provide an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mMcc0IF1hV0&#34;&gt;awesome YouTube channel for Emacs starter guide&lt;/a&gt;.
I highly recommend this guy&amp;rsquo;s series if you want to see how traditional editor is more than capable of
making you productive in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get more inspired/see whats possible then &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B6jfrrwR10k&#34;&gt;this video might be useful for starter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VADudzQGvU8&#34;&gt;video( The editor of lifetime)&lt;/a&gt; might be good for your weekend to see the history, design decision and the evolution of Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, enough of Emacs. Hopefully, next month I will write my experience with &lt;strong&gt;org-mode&lt;/strong&gt; and other
 plugins I used daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-tmux-spliting-panes&#34;&gt;2. Tmux: Spliting Panes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the idea of sitting in the Terminal continues. I want my terminal to support 2 windows, 1 for &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; and
the other for &lt;code&gt;emacs&lt;/code&gt;. I use emacs for taking notes, work logs and journal with &lt;code&gt;org-mode&lt;/code&gt;. I occasionally
need to edit swift code in Emacs but I can if I have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install &lt;strong&gt;tmux&lt;/strong&gt;, please &lt;a href=&#34;http://kandelvijaya.com/2016/10/15/spicingterminal/&#34;&gt;refer to this blog&lt;/a&gt; I wrote
last month. Anyways, issue this command to quickly install tmux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ brew install tmux
$ tmux ;; to run tmux
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splitting the pane with tmux.
1. &lt;code&gt;CTRL + b&lt;/code&gt; then type &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt;
   creates a pane vertically.
2. &lt;code&gt;CTRL + b&lt;/code&gt; then type &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;
   creates a pane horizontally.
3. &lt;code&gt;CTRL + b&lt;/code&gt; then type &lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt; (not Zero)
   switches to another pane
4. &lt;code&gt;$exit&lt;/code&gt;
   close the current pane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my setup, I usually put a pane on top for git related work. The lower on runs &lt;code&gt;emacs&lt;/code&gt; and I have TODOs and
work log on that. Its quite handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;xcode&#34;&gt;XCode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-delete-to-the-end-of-line&#34;&gt;1. Delete to the end of line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the most people, to delete a entire line, we Select it and then delete selection. i.e
CMD + SHIFT + -&amp;gt; , then DEL. Or you use the mouse to make the selection and then delete it.
The point is this is 2 step process. Wait, there is a 1 key binding to do it.
&lt;code&gt;CONTROL + K&lt;/code&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will delete to the end of the line. The same key binding works for Emacs too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-final-resort&#34;&gt;2. Final Resort&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one might be a old school tips, nonetheless it needs to be put into picture. When everything is fine,
and XCode does something beyond your expectation. All you need is to clear artifacts. Every iOS developer
knows this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean build, Try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quit and Restart XCode, Try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove derived data, or change the path, Try.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restart your mac. [This is the least recommended]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, I&amp;rsquo;m using Xcode8 and I had 2 interesting issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If somewhere in your code base there is a extension on &lt;code&gt;UIButton&lt;/code&gt;, you cant connect &lt;code&gt;@IBAction&lt;/code&gt; from
xib to UIView subclass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When compiling large project, the compiler optionally stops at various points and gives compile error.
I knew there was no error in it. I just changed some trivial code. However, I just run &lt;code&gt;CMD + R&lt;/code&gt; multiple
times to bypass each false error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope Xcode 8.2 fixes those issues. Until then, Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GTX [Git, Terminal, Xcode] 2tips for October</title>
      <link>http://kandelvijaya.com/gtxmonthly/gtxTips_oct2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 16:10:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kandelvijaya.com/gtxmonthly/gtxTips_oct2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gtx&#34;&gt;GTX:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned to find 2 tips for Git, Terminal and Xcode each, last weekend. Which should help me be more productive at work. Later, I thought to write it up and shere. This should be a series of mini tips, each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GTX stands for Git, Terminal and Xcode. This abbreviation has local scope to this blog only. Other way to say, I made this GTX shortform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gtx-october-2016&#34;&gt;GTX October 2016&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-git&#34;&gt;1. Git&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time is about rewriting history. Yes, &lt;code&gt;rebase&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, lets start by not rewritting history. Just the normal rebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(featureBranch)$ git rebase master 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will take all the changeset that were made in this &lt;code&gt;featureBranch&lt;/code&gt; and insert it on top of &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets rewrite history. Here is a typical log on git during work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git log --oneline
 1ad2  Added support for X device
 2ad3  Dummy Commit
 3ad4  Empty line removal
 4ad5  Algorithm to find view on the screen done!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s admit sometimes we just add &lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt; or remove &lt;code&gt;//TODO:&lt;/code&gt; and call it a fix. Or Dummy Commit. However, I prefer to push my work as perfect commits when possible. Would it be nice, if we could not push those Dummy commit and minor typos we typically make while wrting commits. Well, its pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(featureBranch)$ git rebase -i 4ad5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you will see bunch of text in the terminal, dont be afraid. Its all documented nicely in the git comments if you just look below the bunch of text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would do something like this:
&lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt; is to squash to the last commit. &lt;code&gt;r&lt;/code&gt; is to reword the commit message.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; pick 4ad5  Algorithm to find view on the screen done!
 s 3ad4  Empty line removal
 s 2ad3  Dummy Commit
 r 1ad2  Added support for X device
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save and quit. (&lt;code&gt;:wq&lt;/code&gt; for default editor).
Follow along with the git interruption where you can modify commits. Each time save and return, after changing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After, all is done. It looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(featureBranch)$glog
7ed8 Added support for That device and editied something.
6ed7 Algorithm to find view on the screen done!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See we did rewrite the history. Nice commits. One thing to note is, git takes the changeset and applies follwing the commands like pick, reword, edit &amp;hellip; In the process it creates new commit hash. Its entirely new hash and commit. For the sake of simplicity, commit hash are 4 chars long in this example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CAUTION: Dont rebase what you have already pushed. Don&amp;rsquo;t dare to rebase when you have teammates working on that branch. Do it on yout unpushed branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are 100% certain, that noone except you is working on the pushed branch, then issue this command to force the push to work after rebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git push -f
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-terminal&#34;&gt;2. Terminal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removing a list of local branches except the current one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    (master)$ git branch | grep -v master | xargs git branch -d 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some branches which cannot be removed can be cleaned with &lt;code&gt;git branch -D&lt;/code&gt; command but be responsible for this. &lt;code&gt;xargs&lt;/code&gt; is the utility to process list of lines as arguments. Read more on the man pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colorful man pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have installed &lt;code&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/code&gt; plugin for terminal then you can simply find these:  &lt;code&gt;plugins=(git)&lt;/code&gt; line in &lt;code&gt;~/.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;plugins=(git, colored-man-pages)&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://kandelvijaya.com/2016/10/15/spicingterminal/&#34;&gt;Check this post&lt;/a&gt; to install and configure Oh-My-Zsh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ELSE, follow this link on &lt;a href=&#34;http://unix.stackexchange.com/a/147&#34;&gt;SO&lt;/a&gt; to know how things actually work and set it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-xcode&#34;&gt;3. Xcode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to find where &lt;code&gt;Indent&lt;/code&gt; option is under the menu bar in Xcode. Or say there is a command you know should exist but don&amp;rsquo;t know where it is nested. For example, you want to insert &lt;code&gt;Special character&lt;/code&gt;.  Do you google? OR do you open each menu option and search. Theres a better way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Command + Shift + /&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press this keys and type the command you think your looking for. In this case, I&amp;rsquo;m looking to insert emoji. Thanks to my friend Andrii who showed me this tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kandelvijaya.com/img/commandShiftSearch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cmd+Shift+/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cool part is this command works on every single Mac app. Its a great way to quickly find menu options that you forgot the location, shortcut or existance. Speaking about shortcut, lets get into the second tip of this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning shortcuts makes you productive. Using keyboard to work and navigate is faster. If you want to discuss on mouse vs keybindings then reach out to &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;emacs&lt;/code&gt; user. &lt;em&gt;It would be quite interesting if I were able to show you how many kilometers your finger glide for a month wile working full time as software engineer. Maybe I will post it in comments, if I do that experiment. While you can be the first one too. From my rough estimation, in a month your finger moves 2.5 KM while moving the trackpad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, theres this app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mediaatelier.com/CheatSheet/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cheatsheet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which displays current application&amp;rsquo;s most important shortcuts while you press and hold &lt;strong&gt;Command&lt;/strong&gt; key for little longer thn 3 seconds. It really helps memorize the key bindings and gives you reference ontop of the app context. This app also works on any Mac app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cheers&#34;&gt;Cheers!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for October. Lets see whats for November. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>